Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we have a very dramatic intermediate level lesson for you.
我是Catherine，今天我们为大家准备了一节非常戏剧性的中级课程。
That's right.
没错。
Today we're going to take a look at how a court works, for example in the United States.
今天我们要看看法庭是如何运作的，比如在美国。
So you see that in movies and TV shows a lot, you know, the judge and all that.
所以你在电影和电视节目里经常看到，你知道，法官之类的。
That's right.
没错。
Many of you have seen the movie The Firm or 12 Angry Men.
你们很多人看过电影《律师事务所》或《十二怒汉》。
These are classics in courtroom dramas we say.
这些是法庭剧中的经典之作，我们这么说。
So today we're in a courtroom and there are many characters who are trying to determine
所以今天我们身处法庭，有很多角色正在试图确定
if this person is innocent or guilty.
这个人是有罪还是无罪。
So let's take a listen and find out what's going on.
那么让我们听一听，看看发生了什么。
Your Honor, ladies and gentlemen of the jury, my client Robert Malone has been accused of
法官大人，陪审团的女士们先生们，我的当事人Robert Malone被指控犯下
a crime he did not commit.
一项他没有犯下的罪行。
The prosecution has accused my client of being a pickpocket.
控方指控我的当事人是一名扒手。
I know we have heard the testimony of many people here today.
我知道我们今天听到了很多人的证词。
People who claim the defendant, my client, stole their wallets.
那些声称被告，也就是我的当事人，偷了他们钱包的人。
I feel sorry for these victims.
我为这些受害者感到难过。
I really do.
我真的感到难过。
But my client is innocent.
但我的当事人是无辜的。
Let's look at the facts.
让我们看看事实。
Number one, these so-called witnesses did not actually see the defendant steal anything.
第一，这些所谓的目击者并没有亲眼看到被告偷任何东西。
Number two, when the police stopped him, he did not have any of the stolen wallets.
第二，当警察拦住他时，他身上没有任何被偷的钱包。
There is no evidence.
没有证据。
Therefore, ladies and gentlemen of the jury, I ask you to think carefully before giving
因此，陪审团的女士们先生们，我请求你们在给出
your verdict.
你们的裁决之前仔细思考。
Look at the facts.
看看事实。
Look at the evidence.
看看证据。
My client is innocent.
我的当事人是无辜的。
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury, have you reached a verdict?
陪审团的女士们先生们，你们达成裁决了吗？
Yes, Your Honor.
是的，法官大人。
Our verdict is not guilty.
我们的裁决是无罪。
Thank you so much.
非常感谢。
You were great.
你太棒了。
Thank you for all your hard work.
感谢你的辛勤工作。
You're welcome, Robert.
不客气，Robert。
I knew you were innocent, so my job was easy.
我知道你是无辜的，所以我的工作很容易。
Take care of yourself, okay?
照顾好自己，好吗？
Thanks once again.
再次感谢。
Hey, where's my wallet?
嘿，我的钱包呢？
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So you probably heard a lot of technical words that are specifically related to the courtroom,
所以你可能听到了很多专门与法庭、
to lawyers, and the laws.
律师和法律相关的技术词汇。
So why don't we take a look at some of those now in Language Takeaway.
那么我们现在在“语言要点”环节来看看其中一些。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
The first Language Takeaway we're looking at today is all about people.
今天我们看的第一个语言要点全是关于人的。
So people you will find in a courtroom.
也就是你在法庭上会见到的人。
Who's the first person on our list, Marco?
我们列表上的第一个人是谁，Marco？
So the top person would be the judge.
最高级别的人就是法官。
Now you didn't really see this word judge in the dialogue, right?
你在对话中并没有真正看到“法官”这个词，对吧？
You did hear though the phrase, Your Honor.
但你确实听到了“法官大人”这个短语。
Your Honor.
法官大人。
So Your Honor.
所以是“法官大人”。
So that's how you talk to a judge.
这就是你称呼法官的方式。
You always add Your Honor before it or something like that?
你总是在前面加上“法官大人”之类的吗？
That's right.
没错。
So you know we say Mr. President when we're talking to Barack Obama.
所以你知道我们跟巴拉克·奥巴马说话时会说“总统先生”。
But if we're talking to a judge, he's a special person in American society.
但如果我们跟法官说话，他是美国社会中的特殊人物。
So we call him or her Your Honor.
所以我们称呼他或她为“法官大人”。
Your Honor.
法官大人。
Okay.
好的。
So we have the judge.
所以我们有法官。
That's our first person.
那是我们的第一个人。
Who else do we have?
还有谁呢？
So we have the judge and now we have a group of 12 people who will ultimately decide if
所以我们有法官，现在还有一组12个人，他们将最终决定
the person is guilty or not.
这个人是否有罪。
That's right.
没错。
So these people are normal.
所以这些人是普通人。
They come from all different parts of society and they will decide what to do with this
他们来自社会的各个不同阶层，他们将决定如何处理这个
person.
人。
Is he guilty or is she innocent?
他是有罪还是她无罪？
This group is called the jury.
这个群体叫做陪审团。
So the jury is a group of normal citizens who will listen to both sides of the story
所以陪审团是一群普通公民，他们会听取双方的故事，
and will then decide if the person committed the crime or didn't commit the crime.
然后决定这个人是否犯了罪。
That's right.
没错。
A jury.
陪审团。
And the big question is, who's fighting?
而关键问题是，谁在对抗？
We have two sides.
我们有两方。
Someone who is upset and someone who is defending themselves.
一方是感到不满的人，另一方是自我辩护的人。
The person who is upset, this is the prosecution.
感到不满的一方，这就是控方。
Okay.
好的。
So the prosecution has a group of lawyers that are called the prosecutors, right?
所以控方有一群律师，他们被称为检察官，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
And they're trying to prove that that person committed the crime.
他们试图证明那个人犯了罪。
For example, I say that Marco burned down my house.
比如，我说马可烧了我的房子。
I go to court, I say I am the prosecution.
我去法庭，我说我是控方。
I want him to pay me for my house.
我要他赔偿我的房子。
So I'm the prosecution.
所以我是控方。
Okay.
好的。
So you're trying to not only prove that I committed the crime, but also trying to get
所以你不仅要证明我犯了罪，还要让我
me to pay for the damage that I caused.
赔偿我造成的损失。
Exactly.
完全正确。
So in this case, the prosecution says, this man stole my wallet.
所以在这个案例中，控方说，这个人偷了我的钱包。
He's a pickpocket.
他是个扒手。
And who's the pickpocket?
那扒手是谁？
Or maybe the pickpocket.
或者可能是那个扒手。
Who's the other side of this?
另一方是谁？
The defendant.
被告。
Defend, defendant.
辩护，被告。
Think about the word here.
想想这个词。
To defend is to stand up for yourself, to protect yourself.
辩护就是为自己站出来，保护自己。
So the defendant says, listen, no, that's not true.
所以被告说，听着，不，那不是真的。
I am not a pickpocket.
我不是扒手。
I didn't do that.
我没做那事。
So we have the prosecution and the defense.
所以我们有控方和辩方。
And the person who might be guilty, the person who did the thing or didn't do the thing,
而那个可能有罪的人，做了或没做那件事的人，
is called the defendant.
被称为被告。
So in your example again about the crime that maybe I burnt your house down or I didn't,
所以再用你的例子，关于我可能烧了你的房子或没烧，
I would be the defendant and my lawyers would constitute my defense.
我会是被告，我的律师会组成我的辩护团队。
Yeah, they are your defense.
是的，他们是你的辩护方。
Okay.
好的。
So very technical words, but the important thing to remember here is defendant.
所以这些是很专业的词，但这里要记住的重点是被告。
All right.
好的。
Good.
很好。
So now we have one key element that is also a person.
现在我们有一个关键元素，也是一个人。
We have the witness.
我们有证人。
All right, so the basic idea like you said is we have to tell a story.
好的，就像你说的，基本想法是我们得讲一个故事。
My story is that you burned down my house.
我的故事是你烧了我的房子。
And you say, no, I didn't.
而你说，不，我没烧。
Prove it.
拿出证据。
I say, I can.
我说，我能。
Someone saw you with a lighter.
有人看到你拿着打火机。
So this person is my witness.
所以这个人就是我的证人。
That means that he or she saw what happened.
这意味着他或她看到了发生的事情。
So someone who sees a crime is a witness to that crime.
所以看到犯罪的人就是那个犯罪的证人。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So a lot of people are in the courtroom.
所以法庭里有很多人。
A lot of things are happening.
很多事情在发生。
So I think we should listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back to look at some more
所以我觉得我们应该再听一遍对话，然后回来看看更多
words on Language Takeaway Part 2.
语言小课堂第二部分的词。
Your Honor, ladies and gentlemen of the jury, my client Robert Malone has been accused of
法官大人，陪审团的女士们先生们，我的当事人罗伯特·马龙被指控犯下
a crime he did not commit.
一项他没有犯的罪行。
The prosecution has accused my client of being a pickpocket.
控方指控我的当事人是扒手。
I know we have heard the testimony of many people here today.
我知道我们今天听到了很多人的证词。
People who claim the defendant, my client, stole their wallets.
那些声称被告，也就是我的当事人，偷了他们钱包的人。
I feel sorry for these victims.
我为这些受害者感到难过。
I really do.
我真的很难过。
But my client is innocent.
但我的当事人是无辜的。
Let's look at the facts.
让我们看看事实。
Number one, these so-called witnesses did not actually see the defendant steal anything.
第一，这些所谓的证人并没有实际看到被告偷任何东西。
Number two, when the police stopped him, he did not have any of the stolen wallets.
第二，当警察拦住他时，他身上没有任何被偷的钱包。
There is no evidence.
没有证据。
Therefore, ladies and gentlemen of the jury, I ask you to think carefully before giving
因此，陪审团的女士们先生们，我请你们在给出
your verdict.
你们的裁决之前仔细思考。
Look at the facts.
看看事实。
Look at the evidence.
看看证据。
My client is innocent.
我的当事人是无辜的。
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury, have you reached a verdict?
陪审团的女士们先生们，你们达成裁决了吗？
Yes, Your Honor.
是的，法官大人。
Our verdict is not guilty.
我们的裁决是无罪。
Thank you so much.
非常感谢。
You were great.
你太棒了。
Thank you for all your hard work.
感谢你所有的辛勤工作。
You're welcome, Robert.
不客气，罗伯特。
I knew you were innocent, so my job was easy.
我知道你是无辜的，所以我的工作很容易。
Take care of yourself, okay?
照顾好自己，好吗？
Thanks once again.
再次感谢。
Hey, where's my wallet?
嘿，我的钱包呢？
I love it when we do this.
我喜欢我们做这个的时候。
So many words.
这么多词。
So much language to take away.
这么多语言点可以学。
That's right.
没错。
So now we're going to take a look at the second part of language takeaway where we have another
现在我们来看语言点学习的第二部分，这里还有另外
set of four words that we want to take a look at.
四个词要学习。
Language takeaway.
语言点学习。
All right.
好的。
The first is actually two words.
第一个实际上是两个词。
We have two opposites.
我们有一对反义词。
Okay?
明白吗？
So you said earlier, the jury has to make a decision.
你之前说过，陪审团必须做出决定。
The jury has to decide, is the defendant innocent or guilty?
陪审团必须决定，被告是有罪还是无罪？
Okay.
好的。
These are two important adjectives.
这是两个重要的形容词。
Innocent.
无辜的。
What does this mean?
这是什么意思？
So if he is innocent, that means he did not commit the crime.
如果他无辜，那就意味着他没有犯罪。
He is not responsible for what happened.
他对发生的事情不负责任。
He did not steal the wallets.
他没有偷钱包。
Okay.
好的。
So we often say babies are so innocent.
所以我们常说婴儿很天真。
Right.
对。
They can't do anything.
他们什么坏事都做不了。
They can't do anything wrong.
他们不会做错事。
Right.
对。
So guilty would be the opposite.
所以有罪就是反义词。
That's right.
没错。
So usually when someone is guilty, they're sad, they feel bad, you want them to pay you.
通常当一个人有罪时，他们会难过、感到愧疚，你希望他们赔偿你。
And they go to jail.
然后他们进监狱。
Yeah.
是的。
In bad situations, they go to jail.
在糟糕的情况下，他们会进监狱。
If you burn down my house, of course you're going to go to jail.
如果你烧了我的房子，你当然要进监狱。
Right.
对。
All right.
好的。
So guilty means you did a crime.
所以有罪意味着你犯了罪。
You did a bad thing.
你做了坏事。
So we talked about the prosecution and the defense of the defendant.
我们谈到了控方和辩方对被告的辩护。
And what happens is they also present some key elements that will prove if the person
然后他们会提出一些关键要素，来证明这个人
is innocent or guilty.
是有罪还是无罪。
And those elements are called evidence.
这些要素被称为证据。
That's right.
没错。
So back to this idea, we tell a story.
回到这个想法，我们讲述一个故事。
Maybe a witness can help us tell our story.
也许证人可以帮助我们讲述故事。
But as you say, evidence is stuff.
但正如你所说，证据是实物。
It's things.
是具体的东西。
So in the case of the house, I could say you have matches and you smell like smoke and
所以在房子这个案例中，我可以说你有火柴，而且你身上有烟和油的味道。
oil.
This is evidence for me to use to show that you are guilty.
这就是我用来证明你有罪的证据。
Right.
对。
So in this case, do we have any evidence?
那么在这个案例中，我们有证据吗？
There's no evidence, says the defendant.
被告说，没有证据。
Right.
对。
All right.
好的。
So evidence is proof.
所以证据就是证明。
It's physical proof.
是实物证明。
Yeah.
是的。
And most of the times when you see movies or TV shows, they will find, I don't know,
大多数时候，你在电影或电视节目里看到，他们会找到，比如，
like maybe a fingerprint that's evidence or somebody's glasses.
指纹作为证据，或者某人的眼镜。
A cell phone.
一部手机。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So evidence.
所以证据。
This is very important when you want to build a case.
这在构建案件时非常重要。
Finally, at the end of a trial, we have a verdict.
最后，在审判结束时，我们会有裁决。
Now, what is a verdict?
那么，什么是裁决？
Well a verdict is a final decision or a conclusion in which the jury says, yeah, the person is
裁决是陪审团做出的最终决定或结论，说，是的，这个人
guilty or he's not guilty, he's innocent.
有罪，或者他无罪，他是无辜的。
So we use this word usually to reach a verdict.
所以我们通常用这个词来说“达成裁决”。
The jury reaches a verdict.
陪审团达成裁决。
Now it's interesting why we say to reach because a jury is not just one person.
有趣的是为什么我们说“达成”，因为陪审团不是一个人。
A jury is many people.
陪审团是很多人。
And so these people have to decide together.
所以这些人必须一起决定。
They have to argue.
他们必须争论。
They have to make a conclusion that everyone agrees on.
他们必须达成一个所有人都同意的结论。
And this is to reach a conclusion, to reach a verdict because they have to travel there.
这就是“达成结论”、“达成裁决”，因为他们需要一起努力
They have to go together and figure it out.
去弄清楚。
Right.
对。
That's very, very important.
这非常重要。
So the jury reaches a verdict.
所以陪审团达成裁决。
And we did have one other phrase that's very interesting.
我们还有一个非常有趣的短语。
It doesn't quite fit with the other ones.
它和其他词不太一样。
We heard this phrase from the defendant.
我们从被告那里听到了这个短语。
The lawyer says, so these so-called witnesses didn't actually see anything.
律师说，这些所谓的证人实际上什么也没看到。
What is so-called?
“所谓的”是什么意思？
So he's being sarcastic when he uses this phrase, so-called, right?
所以他用“所谓的”这个短语时是在讽刺，对吧？
That's why even his tone changes, these so-called witnesses.
这就是为什么他的语气都变了，这些所谓的证人。
So it's a way of expressing sarcasm.
所以这是一种表达讽刺的方式。
He's saying they say they're witnesses, but they're not really because they didn't see
他在说他们自称是证人，但实际上不是，因为他们没看到
anything.
任何东西。
Right.
对。
So so-called means you say that they are, but they're not really.
所以“所谓的”意思是你说他们是，但他们实际上不是。
Right.
对。
I could also say, your so-called lawyer thinks he can help you, but he can't.
我也可以说，你所谓的律师以为他能帮你，但他帮不了。
Right.
对。
That means I don't think your lawyer is very good.
那意味着我认为你的律师不怎么样。
I don't think he's a real lawyer.
我不认为他是个真正的律师。
Right.
对。
Or sometimes people say, my so-called friend stood me up last night.
或者有时人们会说，我所谓的朋友昨晚放我鸽子了。
Oh, so it's not really a friend.
哦，所以那不算真正的朋友。
He's not really a friend.
他不是真正的朋友。
Exactly.
没错。
So-called.
所谓的。
All right.
好了。
That's another good one.
这又是一个好词。
Let's listen to this dialogue one more time.
让我们再听一遍这段对话。
Really think about some of the words you heard today, and we'll be back in a moment.
认真想想你今天听到的一些词，我们一会儿回来。
Your Honor, ladies and gentlemen of the jury.
法官大人，陪审团的女士们先生们。
My client, Robert Malone, has been accused of a crime he did not commit.
我的当事人罗伯特·马龙被指控犯了一项他没有犯的罪行。
The prosecution has accused my client of being a pickpocket.
控方指控我的当事人是个扒手。
I know we have heard the testimony of many people here today.
我知道我们今天听到了很多人的证词。
People who claim the defendant, my client, stole their wallets.
那些声称被告，也就是我的当事人，偷了他们钱包的人。
I feel sorry for these victims.
我为这些受害者感到难过。
I really do.
我真的很难过。
But my client is innocent.
但我的当事人是无辜的。
Let's look at the facts.
让我们看看事实。
Number one, these so-called witnesses did not actually see the defendant steal anything.
第一，这些所谓的证人并没有亲眼看到被告偷任何东西。
Number two, when the police stopped him, he did not have any of the stolen wallets.
第二，当警察拦住他时，他身上没有任何被偷的钱包。
There is no evidence.
没有证据。
Therefore, ladies and gentlemen of the jury, I ask you to think carefully before giving
因此，陪审团的女士们先生们，我请你们在做出
your verdict.
裁决之前仔细思考。
Look at the facts.
看看事实。
Look at the evidence.
看看证据。
My client is innocent.
我的当事人是无辜的。
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury, have you reached a verdict?
陪审团的女士们先生们，你们达成裁决了吗？
Yes, Your Honor.
是的，法官大人。
Our verdict is not guilty.
我们的裁决是无罪。
Thank you so much.
非常感谢。
You were great.
你太棒了。
Thank you for all your hard work.
感谢你的辛勤工作。
You're welcome, Robert.
不客气，罗伯特。
I knew you were innocent, so my job was easy.
我知道你是无辜的，所以我的工作很容易。
Take care of yourself, okay?
照顾好自己，好吗？
Thanks once again.
再次感谢。
Hey, where's my wallet?
嘿，我的钱包呢？
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now a very interesting situation with the courtroom dramas.
所以现在法庭剧里出现了一个非常有趣的情况。
And I've heard that all the people in the jury have to agree in order for them to reach
我听说陪审团的所有人都必须同意才能达成
a verdict, right?
裁决，对吧？
So if one of them is not convinced that the person is, for example, guilty, then they
所以如果其中一个人没有被说服，比如认为有罪，那么他们
have to keep on deliberating.
就得继续审议。
That's the word, right?
是这个词，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So basically, the jury is always alone in a room.
所以基本上，陪审团总是单独待在一个房间里。
Maybe they have a guard, but they're not supposed to talk to journalists or friends of the defendant
也许有个警卫，但他们不应该和记者或被告的朋友
or anyone because their decision is supposed to be pure.
或任何人交谈，因为他们的决定应该是纯粹的。
So they talk, and sometimes it takes 10 minutes.
所以他们讨论，有时只需要10分钟。
Everyone agrees this person is guilty or this person is innocent.
每个人都同意这个人有罪或这个人无罪。
But sometimes they don't agree.
但有时他们意见不一致。
And it can be one day, two days, a week, two weeks, a month trying to decide what to do.
可能是一天、两天、一周、两周、一个月来试图决定怎么做。
I remember in the OJ Simpson case, the jury took a long time to figure out what they were
我记得在O.J.辛普森案中，陪审团花了很长时间才弄清楚他们
going to do.
要怎么做。
And they said that the jury are common citizens.
而且他们说陪审团是由普通公民组成的。
They're normal people.
他们是普通人。
So what happens in their jobs if they can't go to work because they're doing this?
那如果他们因为做这个而不能去上班，他们的工作怎么办？
Well, in America, this job is called jury duty.
嗯，在美国，这种工作叫陪审义务。
And so someone will send you a letter, and they say, listen, you need to come do jury
所以有人会给你寄一封信，他们说，听着，你需要来履行陪审
duty and you help be a part of the jury.
义务，帮助成为陪审团的一员。
And your job, they can't make you come because this is a service for the government.
而你的工作，他们不能强迫你来，因为这是为政府服务。
So it's above everything else.
所以它高于一切。
It's above.
它高于一切。
You get your normal pay.
你还能拿到正常工资。
There's no problem.
没问题。
But it just don't work.
但就是不管用。
Okay.
好吧。
So they can't fire you if you're in jury duty for like five days or a month or whatever.
所以如果你要当陪审员五天或一个月或更久，他们不能因此解雇你。
No, they can't.
对，他们不能。
That's illegal.
那是违法的。
Wow.
哇。
That's really interesting.
那真有意思。
But a lot of people I've heard don't like to go to jury duty for some reason.
但我听说很多人出于某种原因不喜欢去当陪审员。
Is it tedious?
是因为很枯燥吗？
No, it's probably very boring.
不，可能很无聊。
I've never done it, but it's probably very boring.
我没当过，但可能很无聊。
I would imagine so.
我也这么觉得。
All right.
好了。
Well, that's a very interesting topic.
嗯，这是个很有趣的话题。
I'm sure in your countries, laws are handled differently.
我相信在你们国家，法律处理方式不同。
Maybe you don't have a courtroom.
也许你们没有法庭。
Maybe you have like in England, people wear wigs.
也许像英国那样，人们戴假发。
And black robes.
还有黑袍。
So let us know how it works in your countries.
所以告诉我们你们国家的情况吧。
We'll see everyone at our website EnglishPod.com.
我们会在网站 EnglishPod.com 上见大家。
And of course, if you have any questions or comments, you can leave those there as well.
当然，如果有任何问题或评论，也可以留在那里。
See you on the website and happy studies.
网站上见，祝学习愉快。
Bye everyone.
大家再见。